Welcome back to A Push in under 3
minutes, so no time for intros. Let's
get into it. Oh, the Roaring [music]
20s. What a time to be alive. Oops,
sorry, but that's actually supposed to
be next topic. Lots of people like
studying the 1920s in American history
because of how much cool culture there
was, which is why we refer to it as the
Roaring 20s. Right now, we're going to
talk about what facilitated and caused
this quote Roaring 20s. Basically, this
comes down to two things: new technology
and mass media. Let's first talk about
the technology. And for this we will
look at two people. Let's start with
Henry Ford. Ford here popularized
something very revolutionary known as
assembly lines. Meaning he broke down
production into simple repeated steps
causing a faster output which would then
cause the price of goods to go down. The
second part to this is something called
scientific management where you
prioritize efficiency over everything
else. The man attributed to this is a
man named Frederick Taylor. Oh, and
before we move on, the biggest
innovation in this time period and
arguably in the entirety of world
history will be the automobile. It's
truly indescribable how much the
automobile changes everything. Commuting
changes, roads will be built, gas
stations, and motel are made. And it
would cause an unforeseen level of
suburban growth. But now, let's go over
to our second thing and talk about the
media. Because other than the
automobile, you have two more things
that boomed in this time period. Cinema
and the radio. With cinema, we are
obviously talking about the growth of
Hollywood and movies which would give
Americans shared celebrities, fashion,
slang, and even values. The more
impactful one here though is probably
radios because now instead of waiting
for a newspaper, people can have live
broadcasts, news, music, sports,
advertising. And the big importance here
is that people across the country are
all listening to the same stuff. This
created a consumer economy, meaning
people were buying appliances, cars, and
entertainment, often through credit and
installment plans. This would also
facilitate the means of which cultures
will spread across America throughout
the 20s, especially regional ones, and
make something like the Roaring 20s
possible. On the screen now are AP style
questions for this topic. Pause now.
I'll put the answers on the screen now.
I will see you in the next one.